this problem
asks us to write a case statement that
prints go
if our local variable stoplight equals
green
slow down if our local variable
stoplight equals yellow
and stop if stoplight equals red
so in this case we're comparing multiple
values to the value referenced by our
variable stoplight
and this is an example of when a case
statement comes in handy
the case that we are comparing to all
the conditions
is stoplight
will be equal to either green yellow or
red
the value of stoplight will be assigned
randomly as we can see on line one
within a case statement we use the
reserved word when
[Music]
and then provide our condition each
condition that we provide to
when will be compared to the value of
stoplight
so following along with our problem
description we'll first compare the
string
green to the value of stoplight
we also want to compare yellow
and finally red
the case statement will execute the code
in whichever branch the condition
evaluates to true
we want to print the string go if
stoplight is equal to green
print slow down if stop light is equal
to yellow
and print stop when stop light is equal
to red
i'm going to output the value of
stoplight on line 3 so that we can
see what it is and compare it to the
output that we get
so stoplight was red and we output the
string stop
yellow and we output slow down
green and we output go
so that's perfect on line 10
we don't actually need to compare
stoplight to the string red
stoplight in this case only has three
possible values
green yellow and red if we've reached
line 10 of our code
and stoplight wasn't equal to green or
yellow
then we know it must be red
so just like an if statement we can
place an else branch
in our case statement this tells ruby
that
if none of the prior branches in our
case statement were executed
then execute the code within this else
branch
in this case we know that the stop light
is red if we've reached line 10
and we want to output the string stop
and you can see that it's working as we
expect
case statements work similarly to if
statements
but they're a nice concise way to
compare multiple values to a single case
you